<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>DevGuidance.com</title><link>https://www.devguidance.com/</link><description>Recent content on DevGuidance.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 12:00:10 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.devguidance.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Integration testing setup for Java REST API applications with database persistence</title><link>https://www.devguidance.com/posts/integration-testing-setup-for-java-rest-api-applications-with-database-persistence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 12:00:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.devguidance.com/posts/integration-testing-setup-for-java-rest-api-applications-with-database-persistence/</guid><description>Introduction You may find the previous article a bit theoretical. So this one is about how to set up step-by-step integration testing for the REST API app that persists data to the SQL database. Also, the idea may be applicable also for NoSQL DB testing. The application is simplified as much as possible, as the purpose of the article is to give the idea of proper integration testing. The repository link with the complete example is available here.</description></item><item><title>How to choose right scope for a test</title><link>https://www.devguidance.com/posts/how-to-choose-right-scope-for-a-test/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 20:28:17 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.devguidance.com/posts/how-to-choose-right-scope-for-a-test/</guid><description>Test scope introduction Rather talk about specific definition of test scope let&amp;rsquo;s review list of different test types ordered from higher to lower scope.
Basically, the more things like methods, endpoints, databases, services, apps are involved in test the higher is scope.
How to choose right scope for test There is no clear recommendation how to choose scope for test. Instead of reeling on approximate count concept like test pyramid which inherently makes sense, but besides there are definitely more things that should be considered while choosing test type.</description></item></channel></rss>